They could solve nature's biggest mystery if only they had a clue.
Strange Wilderness is a comedy, adventure film directed by Fred Wolf.
With the ratings dropping for a wilderness-themed TV show, two
animal fans go to the Andes in search of Bigfoot.
Peter, played by Steve Zahn.
Fred, played by Allen Covert.
Cooker, played by Jonah Hill.
Whitaker, played by Kevin Heffernan.
Cheryl, played by Ashley Scott.
Ed Lawson, played by Jeff Garlin.
Strange Wilderness is a 2008 American comedy adventure film produced by Adam Sandler's
production company Happy Madison Productions and distributed by Paramount Pictures.
Directed by Fred Wolf (in his feature length directorial debut), who also co-wrote the film with Peter Gaulke, the film stars Steve Zahn, Allen Covert, Jonah
Hill, Kevin Heffernan, Ashley Scott, Peter Dante, Harry Hamlin, Robert Patrick, Joe Don Baker, Justin Long, Jeff Garlin, and Ernest Borgnine.
Production took place in 2005 but the film did not receive a
theatrical release until February 1, 2008.
Strange Wilderness centers around the crew members of the titular fictional nature show heading to
Ecuador to investigate a Bigfoot sighting in order to keep the show from being cancelled.
The film was critically panned and was a box office bomb,
making $6.9 million against a $20 million budget.
The tone is lighthearted.